<slice name="文档">
  <file path="AGENTS.md">
# claude-video / watch skill

Agent Skills package that gives an agent a video input. Installable across Claude Code (most common host), Codex, Cursor, GitHub Copilot, and 50+ other [Agent Skills](https://agentskills.io) hosts. Pure-stdlib Python that orchestrates `yt-dlp` + `ffmpeg` and an optional Whisper API.

## Structure

- `skills/watch/SKILL.md` — canonical skill contract the model reads when `/watch` fires. Source of truth for behavior across every host.
- `skills/watch/scripts/watch.py` — entry point; orchestrates download → frames → transcript.
- `skills/watch/scripts/{download,frames,transcribe,whisper,setup,config}.py` — yt-dlp wrapper, ffmpeg frame extraction + auto-fps, caption/Whisper transcription, preflight/installer, shared config.
- `skills/watch/scripts/build-skill.sh` — builds `dist/watch.skill` for claude.ai upload (dev-only).
- `hooks/` — Claude Code SessionStart setup-status hook (Claude Code only).
- `.claude-plugin/` — `plugin.json` + `marketplace.json` (Claude Code plugin + local marketplace).
- `.codex-plugin/plugin.json` — Codex/agents manifest; `&quot;skills&quot;: &quot;./skills/&quot;` points the Agent Skills CLI at the self-contained skill folder.
- `.agents/plugins/marketplace.json` — agents marketplace listing pointing at the repo-root plugin.
- `CLAUDE.md` → `@AGENTS.md` — generic-agent entry point.
- `tests/` — pytest suite (ffmpeg-synthesized clips; no network).

## Orientation

- The product is the slash-command-invoked skill (`/watch &lt;url-or-path&gt; [question]`), not a CLI. `scripts/watch.py` is implementation. Features must work across every harness the skill installs into, not just Claude Code.
- **The skill is one self-contained folder: `skills/watch/`.** SKILL.md and `scripts/` are siblings inside it. This is what lets `npx skills add` copy a working skill as a unit — do NOT move SKILL.md or `scripts/` back to the repo root, or non-Claude installers will copy SKILL.md without the scripts.
- **Path resolution is harness-agnostic.** SKILL.md resolves `SKILL_DIR` as the directory of the SKILL.md the model just Read, then runs `${SKILL_DIR}/scripts/...`. Do NOT reintroduce `${CLAUDE_SKILL_DIR}` (Claude-Code-only) — it is unset on Codex/Cursor/agents and breaks every script call there.
- **No `commands/` wrapper.** `/watch` is derived from SKILL.md frontmatter (`name: watch` + `user-invocable: true`). A separate command file creates a duplicate slash command.

## Install surfaces

| Surface | Install |
|---------|---------|
| Claude Code | `/plugin marketplace add bradautomates/claude-video` then `/plugin install watch@claude-video` |
| Codex / Cursor / Copilot / +50 | `npx skills add bradautomates/claude-video -g` |
| claude.ai (web) | upload `dist/watch.skill` (built by `skills/watch/scripts/build-skill.sh`) |

## Commands

```bash
# Tests (stdlib + pytest; ffmpeg required for frame tests)
.venv/bin/pytest -q                # or: python3 -m pytest -q

# Build the claude.ai upload bundle (archives skills/watch/ as the bundle root)
bash skills/watch/scripts/build-skill.sh   # → dist/watch.skill

# Dev: mirror the working tree into the installed Claude Code plugin cache
./dev-sync.sh                       # --dry-run to preview
```

## Rules

- Keep the version in sync across `skills/watch/SKILL.md` (frontmatter), `.claude-plugin/plugin.json`, and `.codex-plugin/plugin.json` when cutting a release.
- Releasing: tag `vX.Y.Z` and push the tag; `.github/workflows/release.yml` builds `dist/watch.skill` and attaches it to the GitHub release.
- Never commit real API keys or `.env` contents; keys live in `~/.config/watch/.env` (mode `0600`) at runtime.

  </file>
  <file path="CHANGELOG.md">
# Changelog

All notable changes to `/watch` are documented here.

## [0.2.0] — 2026-06-29

### Added
- **`--detail` dial** with four modes — `transcript` (captions only, no frames), `efficient` (fast keyframe pass, cap 50), `balanced` (scene-aware, cap 100, default), and `token-burner` (scene-aware, uncapped). Set the default with `WATCH_DETAIL` in `~/.config/watch/.env`.
- **Frame deduplication** (default on; `--no-dedup` to disable). Before the budget cap, a pass downscales each frame to a 16×16 grayscale thumbnail and drops frames whose mean per-pixel difference from the last *kept* frame is within threshold — so the budget goes to distinct content instead of held slides and static recordings. The **Frames** report line shows how many near-duplicates were dropped.
- **Whisper auto-chunking.** Audio over the 25 MB upload cap is split into evenly sized chunks, transcribed per chunk, with segment timestamps shifted back into source time. Partial failures are tolerated — transcription only fails if *every* chunk fails, so length alone no longer breaks it.
- **`--timestamps T1,T2,…`** — grab a frame at each absolute timestamp; reserved against the cap, and the only frames produced under `--detail transcript`.
- **`--no-whisper`** — disable transcription entirely (frames only).
- pytest suite covering config, dedup, download, fixtures, frames, setup, timestamps, watch, and whisper (no network; ffmpeg-synthesized clips).

### Changed
- **Restructured into a self-contained `skills/watch/` package** so `SKILL.md` and its `scripts/` runtime are siblings in one folder. This fixes installs on Codex, Cursor, Copilot, and other Agent Skills hosts: `npx skills add` now copies the skill as a working unit instead of grabbing the root `SKILL.md` without its scripts.
- **Harness-agnostic path resolution** — `SKILL.md` resolves `$SKILL_DIR` from where it was Read instead of the Claude-Code-only `${CLAUDE_SKILL_DIR}`, so script calls work on every host.
- `/watch` is now derived from `SKILL.md` frontmatter; the separate `commands/watch.md` wrapper was dropped to avoid a duplicate slash command.
- `balanced` now full-decodes to detect every scene cut across the whole video. The previous early-exit was faster but kept only the first cuts and dropped the tail of long videos.
- `token-burner` is exempt from the long-video &quot;sparse scan&quot; warning, since it keeps every scene-change frame.
- `--max-frames` is now an override on top of each mode&#x27;s default cap, rather than a fixed default of 80.

### Fixed
- Non-Claude installs (`npx skills add`) were dead on arrival — the installer copied `SKILL.md` without the `scripts/` it shells out to. The self-contained package layout resolves this.

### Removed
- `V2_PLAN.md` and `V2_CONCERNS.md` planning docs.

## [0.1.3] — 2026-05-09

### Fixed
- Windows: `video.info.json` is read as UTF-8 (#4). Previously `Path.read_text()` defaulted to cp1252 on Windows and crashed on yt-dlp&#x27;s UTF-8 output, silently dropping Title/Uploader from the report. Same fix applied to `.env` reads/writes in `whisper.py` and `setup.py`.
- `download.py` now logs info.json parse failures to stderr instead of swallowing them.

### Security
- Hardened subprocess argv against option injection (#2): inserted `--` before the URL in the yt-dlp argv, and tightened `is_url` to reject `-`-prefixed sources and require a non-empty netloc. Resolved video/audio paths to absolute via `Path.resolve()` before passing to `ffmpeg`/`ffprobe`, so a relative path starting with `-` can&#x27;t be misinterpreted as a flag.

## [0.1.2] — 2026-04-24

### Fixed
- Windows console crash: removed the emoji from the long-video warning in `watch.py`; cp1252 consoles couldn&#x27;t encode it.
- `setup.py` now prints `winget` / `pip` install commands on Windows instead of &quot;unsupported platform&quot; — matches what the README already promised.

### Changed
- `SKILL.md` notes that on Windows the scripts must be invoked with `python`, not `python3` (the latter is the Microsoft Store stub on Windows).

## [0.1.1] — 2026-04-24

### Fixed
- Added `commands/watch.md` shim so `/watch` is callable when installed as a Claude Code plugin. Without it, the plugin loaded but the skill wasn&#x27;t exposed as a slash command.
- `scripts/build-skill.sh` now strips `commands/` from the claude.ai `.skill` bundle alongside `hooks/` and `.claude-plugin/`.

## [0.1.0] — 2026-04-24

Initial marketplace release.

### Added
- `/watch &lt;url-or-path&gt; [question]` slash command.
- yt-dlp download with native caption extraction (manual + auto-subs).
- ffmpeg frame extraction with auto-scaled fps (≤2 fps, ≤100 frames, duration-aware budget).
- `--start` / `--end` focused mode with denser frame budget and transcript range filtering.
- Whisper fallback (Groq preferred, OpenAI secondary) for videos without captions.
- `setup.py` preflight: silent `--check`, structured `--json`, and installer that auto-runs `brew install` on macOS.
- Session-start hook that prints a one-line status on first run / partial config.
- `.skill` bundle packaging for claude.ai upload via `scripts/build-skill.sh`.

  </file>
  <file path="CLAUDE.md">
@AGENTS.md

  </file>
  <file path="README.md">
# /watch

**Give Claude the ability to watch any video.**

Claude Code (recommended — auto-updates via marketplace):
```
/plugin marketplace add bradautomates/claude-video
/plugin install watch@claude-video
```

Codex, Cursor, Copilot, Gemini CLI, or any of 50+ [Agent Skills](https://agentskills.io) hosts:
```bash
npx skills add bradautomates/claude-video -g
```
(`-g` installs globally for your user, available across all projects. Drop it to scope per-project.)

More install options (claude.ai web, manual) in the [Install](#install) section below.

Zero config to start — `yt-dlp` and `ffmpeg` install on first run via `brew` on macOS (Linux/Windows print exact commands). Captions cover most public videos for free. Whisper API key is only needed when a video has no captions.

---

Claude can read a webpage, run a script, browse a repo. What it can&#x27;t do, out of the box, is *watch a video*. You paste a YouTube link and it has to either guess from the title or pull a transcript that&#x27;s missing 90% of what&#x27;s on screen.

With Claude Video `/watch` you can paste a URL or a local path, ask a question, and Claude fetches captions first, downloads only what it needs, extracts frames (scene-aware, or fast keyframes at `efficient` detail), pulls a timestamped transcript (free captions when available, Whisper API as fallback), and `Read`s every frame as an image. By the time it answers, it has *seen* the video and *heard* the audio.

```
/watch https://youtu.be/dQw4w9WgXcQ what happens at the 30 second mark?
```

## What people actually use it for

**Analyze someone else&#x27;s content.** `/watch https://youtu.be/&lt;viral-video&gt; what hook did they open with?` Claude looks at the first frames, reads the opening transcript, breaks down the structure. Same for ad creative, competitor launches, podcast intros, anything where the *how* matters as much as the *what*.

**Diagnose a bug from a video.** Someone sends you a screen recording of something broken. `/watch bug-repro.mov what&#x27;s going wrong?` Claude watches the recording, finds the frame where the issue appears, describes what&#x27;s on screen, often catches the cause without you ever opening the file.

**Summarize a video.** `/watch https://youtu.be/&lt;long-thing&gt; summarize this` does the obvious thing — pulls the structure, the key moments, what was actually said and shown. Faster than watching at 2x.

**Cut the hype out of an update video.** `/watch https://youtu.be/&lt;launch-video&gt; what&#x27;s actually new — skip the hype` Strip a &quot;game-changer&quot; feature drop down to the few things that matter, so you get the substance without ten minutes of intro and overselling.

**Turn a playlist into notes.** `/watch https://youtu.be/&lt;video&gt; summarize this to a note` Run it across a series and file a per-video summary, so a channel or course becomes a searchable set of notes instead of hours you have to sit through.

## How it works

1. **You paste a video and a question.** URL (anything yt-dlp supports — YouTube, Loom, TikTok, X, Instagram, plus a few hundred more) or a local path (`.mp4`, `.mov`, `.mkv`, `.webm`).
2. **`yt-dlp` checks captions first.** At `transcript` detail, captioned URLs return without downloading video. Otherwise, or when Whisper needs audio, it downloads only what the run needs.
3. **`ffmpeg` extracts frames at the chosen detail.** `efficient` decodes keyframes only (near-instant); `balanced`/`token-burner` prefer scene-change frames and fall back to the duration-aware uniform sampler when they under-produce. JPEGs are 512px wide by default and clamped to 1998px tall for Claude Read compatibility.
4. **The transcript comes from one of two places.** First try: `yt-dlp` pulls native captions (manual or auto-generated) from the source. Free, instant, accurate-ish. Fallback: extract a mono 16 kHz 64 kbps mp3 audio clip (~480 kB/min) and ship it to Whisper — Groq&#x27;s `whisper-large-v3` (preferred — cheaper and faster) or OpenAI&#x27;s `whisper-1`.
5. **Frames + transcript are handed to Claude.** The script prints frame paths with `t=MM:SS` markers and the transcript with timestamps. Claude `Read`s each frame in parallel — JPEGs render directly as images in its context.
6. **Claude answers grounded in what&#x27;s actually on screen and in the audio.** Not &quot;based on the description&quot; or &quot;according to the title.&quot; It saw the frames. It heard the transcript. It answers the way someone who watched the video would.
7. **Cleanup.** The script prints a working directory at the end. If you&#x27;re not asking follow-ups, Claude removes it.

## Frame budget — why it matters

Token cost is dominated by frames. Every frame is an image; image tokens add up fast. The script&#x27;s auto-fps logic exists so you don&#x27;t blow your context budget on a sparse scan of a 30-minute video that would have been better answered by a focused 30-second window.

| Duration | Default frame budget | What you get |
|----------|---------------------|--------------|
| ≤30 s | ~30 frames | Dense — basically every key moment |
| 30 s - 1 min | ~40 frames | Still dense |
| 1 - 3 min | ~60 frames | Comfortable |
| 3 - 10 min | ~80 frames | Sparse but workable |
| &gt; 10 min | 100 frames (capped modes) | &quot;Sparse scan&quot; warning — re-run focused, or `--detail token-burner` for full uncapped coverage |

When the user names a moment (&quot;around 2:30&quot;, &quot;the last 30 seconds&quot;, &quot;from 0:45 to 1:00&quot;), pass `--start` / `--end`. Focused mode gets denser per-second budgets, capped at 2 fps. Far more useful than a sparse pass over the whole thing.

## Frame deduplication

Frame selection — keyframes (`efficient`), scene-change detection (`balanced`/`token-burner`), or the uniform sampler it falls back to — can still surface near-identical frames: a screen recording that holds one slide for 90 seconds produces a dozen, each billed as a separate image. A dedup pass drops them before frames reach Claude. It runs by default on every frame mode (`--no-dedup` turns it off):

1. One `ffmpeg` call scales each extracted JPEG to a 16×16 grayscale thumbnail. Everything after is pure-stdlib Python — no image libraries.
2. For each frame, compute the **mean absolute difference** against the *last frame that was kept* (average per-pixel brightness change, 0–255 scale).
3. If that difference is at or below the threshold (`2.0`), the frame is a near-duplicate and is dropped. Otherwise it&#x27;s kept and becomes the new reference.
4. The frame-budget cap applies *after* dedup, so the budget is spent on distinct frames.

Comparing against the last *kept* frame (not the previous one) catches slow fades that never trip a frame-to-frame threshold. The threshold is deliberately low and measures absolute brightness rather than structure, so a one-line code diff, a terminal scrolling a row, or two differently-colored flat slides all survive.

The **Frames** line reports what was collapsed, e.g. `6 selected from 14 candidates (… 8 near-duplicates dropped …)`. On always-moving footage nothing is dropped and you pay what you would have anyway.

## Detail modes — measured

The `--detail` dial trades speed and token cost for visual fidelity. Numbers below are from a real run against a **49:08** YouTube video (1280×720, English auto-captions) — a long, mostly-static screen recording, the case that stresses the caps hardest. Extraction times are local CPU against a pre-downloaded copy; the one-time download was **~37 s** / 76 MB, shared by the three frame modes.

| Mode | Engine | Frames | Cap | Extraction time | Temporal coverage | Est. image tokens |
|------|--------|--------|-----|-----------------|-------------------|-------------------|
| `transcript` | none (captions) | 0 | — | **~4.5 s** (one yt-dlp call, no download) | full (text) | 0 (≈26.6k text tokens) |
| `efficient` | keyframe (`-skip_frame nokey`) | 50 | 50 | **~0.5 s** | 0:00 → 49:04 (full) | **~9.8k** |
| `balanced` | scene-change | 100 | 100 | **~20.9 s** | 0:00 → 48:38 (full) | **~19.7k** |
| `token-burner` | scene-change | 116 | uncapped | **~21.0 s** | 0:00 → 48:38 (full) | **~22.8k** |

- **Image tokens** use Anthropic&#x27;s `(width × height) / 750` — at the default 512px width these 720p frames are 512×288, **≈197 tokens/frame**; `--resolution 1024` roughly 4×s that. The transcript is surfaced in every captioned mode and on long videos is often the larger cost.
- **One sampling rule across frame modes.** Each detects all candidates across the full range, then even-samples (first + last always kept) down to its cap. The modes differ only in candidate *source* (keyframes vs. scene cuts) and cap, never in how coverage is spread — so the last frame always lands at the end, not partway through.
- **`efficient` is the speed tier** (~0.5 s) — it only reconstructs keyframes, so it&#x27;s ~40× faster than the scene modes, which decode every frame to find cuts. It can also return *more* frames than `balanced` on low-motion footage (keyframes outnumber scene cuts); &quot;efficient&quot; means fast extraction, not fewer frames.
- **`token-burner` only diverges from `balanced` past the cap.** This clip had 116 cuts, so `balanced` sampled 100 and `token-burner` kept all 116. On high-motion video with hundreds of cuts, `token-burner` keeps everything (and trips the &gt;250-frame token warning) while `balanced` thins to 100.

End-to-end from a cold URL, `transcript` is the cheapest mode by far; the frame modes add the shared ~37 s download on top of the extraction times above.

## Install

| Surface | Install |
|---------|---------|
| **Claude Code** | `/plugin marketplace add bradautomates/claude-video` then `/plugin install watch@claude-video` |
| **Codex, Cursor, Copilot, Gemini CLI, +50 more** | `npx skills add bradautomates/claude-video -g` |
| **claude.ai** (web) | [Download `watch.skill`](https://github.com/bradautomates/claude-video/releases/latest) → Settings → Capabilities → Skills → `+` |
| **Manual / dev** | `git clone` then symlink `skills/watch` into your host&#x27;s skills dir (see below) |

### Claude Code

```
/plugin marketplace add bradautomates/claude-video
/plugin install watch@claude-video
```

Update later with `/plugin update watch@claude-video`.

### Codex, Cursor, Copilot, Gemini CLI, and 50+ other hosts

The [Agent Skills](https://agentskills.io) CLI installs the skill into whatever agents it detects:

```bash
npx skills add bradautomates/claude-video -g
```

`-g` installs globally for your user (`~/.codex/skills`, `~/.cursor/skills`, etc.); drop it to install into the current project instead. Useful flags:

- `-a, --agent &lt;names…&gt;` — target specific hosts, e.g. `-a codex -a cursor`
- `-l, --list` — list the skills in this repo without installing
- `--copy` — copy files instead of symlinking (for filesystems without symlink support)

The CLI discovers the skill from `skills/watch/SKILL.md` and copies the whole folder — `SKILL.md` plus its `scripts/` runtime — as a self-contained unit. `SKILL.md` resolves its own scripts relative to wherever it was installed, so it works the same on every host.

Update later with `npx skills update watch -g`.

### claude.ai (web)

1. [Download `watch.skill`](https://github.com/bradautomates/claude-video/releases/latest) from the latest release.
2. Go to Settings → Capabilities → Skills.
3. Click `+` and drop the file in.

Enable &quot;Code execution and file creation&quot; under Capabilities first — the skill shells out to `ffmpeg` and `yt-dlp`, so it won&#x27;t run without it.

### Manual (developer)

Clone the repo and symlink the self-contained skill folder into your host&#x27;s skills directory — the symlink keeps the install in sync with your working tree as you edit:

```bash
git clone https://github.com/bradautomates/claude-video.git
ln -s &quot;$(pwd)/claude-video/skills/watch&quot; ~/.claude/skills/watch   # or ~/.codex/skills/watch
```

For claude.ai, build the `.skill` bundle from source: `bash skills/watch/scripts/build-skill.sh` produces `dist/watch.skill`.

## First run

On the first `/watch` call, the skill runs `scripts/setup.py --check`. If `ffmpeg` / `yt-dlp` aren&#x27;t on your PATH, or no Whisper API key is set, it walks you through fixing it:

- **macOS** — auto-runs `brew install ffmpeg yt-dlp`.
- **Linux** — prints the exact `apt` / `dnf` / `pipx` commands.
- **Windows** — prints the `winget` / `pip` commands.
- **API key** — scaffolds `~/.config/watch/.env` (mode `0600`) with commented placeholders for `GROQ_API_KEY` (preferred) and `OPENAI_API_KEY`.

After setup, preflight is silent and `/watch` just works. The check is a sub-100ms lookup, so it doesn&#x27;t slow you down on subsequent runs.

## Bring your own keys

Captions cover the majority of public videos for free. The Whisper fallback only kicks in when a video genuinely has no caption track — typically local files, TikToks, some Vimeos, and the occasional caption-less YouTube upload.

| Capability | What you need | Cost |
|------------|---------------|------|
| Download + native captions | `yt-dlp` + `ffmpeg` | Free |
| Whisper fallback (preferred) | [Groq API key](https://console.groq.com/keys) — `whisper-large-v3` | Cheap, fast |
| Whisper fallback (alt) | [OpenAI API key](https://platform.openai.com/api-keys) — `whisper-1` | Standard pricing |
| Disable Whisper entirely | `--no-whisper` | Free, frames-only when no captions |

## Usage

```
/watch https://youtu.be/dQw4w9WgXcQ what happens at the 30 second mark?
/watch https://www.tiktok.com/@user/video/123 summarize this
/watch ~/Movies/screen-recording.mp4 when does the UI break?
/watch https://vimeo.com/123 what tools does she mention?
```

Focused on a specific section — denser frame budget, lower token cost:
```
/watch https://youtu.be/abc --start 2:15 --end 2:45
/watch video.mp4 --start 50 --end 60
/watch &quot;$URL&quot; --start 1:12:00            # from 1h12m to end
```

Other knobs (passed to `scripts/watch.py`):

- `--detail transcript|efficient|balanced|token-burner` — fidelity/speed dial. `transcript` skips frames (transcript only); `efficient` uses fast keyframes (cap 50); `balanced` uses scene-aware frames (cap 100); `token-burner` is scene-aware and uncapped.
- `--timestamps T1,T2,…` — grab a frame at each absolute timestamp (`SS`/`MM:SS`/`HH:MM:SS`). Claude reads the transcript first, then targets the moments the presenter flags (&quot;look here&quot;, &quot;as you can see&quot;). Added on top of the detail frames (reserved against the cap); out-of-window cues are dropped in focus mode; with `--detail transcript` these become the only frames.
- `--max-frames N` — lower the frame cap for a tighter token budget.
- `--resolution W` — bump frame width to 1024 px when Claude needs to read on-screen text (slides, terminals, code).
- `--fps F` — override the auto-fps calculation (still capped at 2 fps).
- `--whisper groq|openai` — force a specific Whisper backend.
- `--no-whisper` — disable transcription entirely; frames only.
- `--no-dedup` — keep near-duplicate frames. By default a frame-delta pass drops frames that are visually near-identical to the one before them (held slides, static screen recordings, paused video), so the frame budget is spent on distinct content; this flag turns that off.
- `--out-dir DIR` — keep working files somewhere specific (default: auto-generated tmp dir).

## Limits

- **Long-video accuracy depends on the detail mode.** On the capped modes (`efficient`, default `balanced`) coverage thins out past ~10 minutes — the frame cap spreads across the whole clip, so the script prints a &quot;sparse scan&quot; warning and you&#x27;re better off re-running focused with `--start`/`--end`. `token-burner` lifts the cap and keeps *every* scene-change frame across the full video, so it stays complete on longer clips at the cost of more image tokens. The 10-minute mark is guidance for the capped modes, not a hard ceiling.
- **Detail is one dial.** Defaults are balanced: scene-aware frames, 2 fps max, 100-frame cap. Use `--detail efficient` for a fast 50-frame keyframe pass, or `--detail token-burner` for uncapped scene candidates. Set `WATCH_DETAIL` in `~/.config/watch/.env` to change the default.

## Structure

```
.
├── skills/watch/                 # self-contained skill — copied as a unit by every installer
│   ├── SKILL.md                  # skill contract — the source of truth across all surfaces
│   └── scripts/
│       ├── watch.py              # entry point — orchestrates download → frames → transcript
│       ├── download.py           # yt-dlp wrapper
│       ├── frames.py             # ffmpeg frame extraction + auto-fps logic
│       ├── transcribe.py         # VTT parsing + dedupe + Whisper orchestration
│       ├── whisper.py            # Groq / OpenAI clients (pure stdlib)
│       ├── config.py             # shared config (~/.config/watch/.env)
│       ├── setup.py              # preflight + installer
│       └── build-skill.sh        # build dist/watch.skill for claude.ai upload (dev-only)
├── hooks/                        # SessionStart status hook (Claude Code only)
├── .claude-plugin/               # plugin.json + marketplace.json (Claude Code)
├── .codex-plugin/                # plugin.json — Codex/agents manifest (&quot;skills&quot;: &quot;./skills/&quot;)
├── .agents/plugins/              # marketplace.json — Agent Skills marketplace listing
├── AGENTS.md → CLAUDE.md         # generic-agent entry point
├── tests/                        # pytest suite (ffmpeg-synthesized clips, no network)
└── .github/workflows/            # release.yml — auto-builds watch.skill on tag push
```

## Develop

```bash
# Run the test suite (stdlib + pytest; ffmpeg required for frame tests):
python3 -m pytest -q

# Build the claude.ai upload bundle:
bash skills/watch/scripts/build-skill.sh      # → dist/watch.skill
```

Releasing: tag `vX.Y.Z`, push the tag. The workflow builds `dist/watch.skill` and attaches it to the GitHub release. Keep the version in sync across `skills/watch/SKILL.md`, `.claude-plugin/plugin.json`, and `.codex-plugin/plugin.json`.

See [CHANGELOG.md](CHANGELOG.md) for version history.

## Open source

MIT license.

Built on `yt-dlp`, `ffmpeg`, and Claude&#x27;s multimodal `Read` tool. Whisper transcription via [Groq](https://groq.com) or [OpenAI](https://openai.com).

Built by Brad Bonanno — I make content about building with AI on [YouTube (@bradbonanno)](https://www.youtube.com/@bradbonanno), and build AI operating systems for businesses at [Solaris Automation](https://www.solarisautomation.io/). If `/watch` saves you from scrubbing through a video, come say hi on the channel.

## Star History

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.star-history.com/?repos=bradautomates%2Fclaude-video&amp;type=date&amp;legend=top-left&quot;&gt;
 &lt;picture&gt;
   &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://api.star-history.com/chart?repos=bradautomates/claude-video&amp;type=date&amp;theme=dark&amp;legend=top-left&quot; /&gt;
   &lt;source media=&quot;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&quot; srcset=&quot;https://api.star-history.com/chart?repos=bradautomates/claude-video&amp;type=date&amp;legend=top-left&quot; /&gt;
   &lt;img alt=&quot;Star History Chart&quot; src=&quot;https://api.star-history.com/chart?repos=bradautomates/claude-video&amp;type=date&amp;legend=top-left&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

---

[github.com/bradautomates/claude-video](https://github.com/bradautomates/claude-video) · [@bradbonanno](https://www.youtube.com/@bradbonanno) · [Solaris Automation](https://www.solarisautomation.io/) · [LICENSE](LICENSE)

  </file>
  <file path="skills/watch/SKILL.md">
---
name: watch
version: &quot;0.2.0&quot;
description: Watch a video (URL or local path). Downloads with yt-dlp, extracts auto-scaled frames with ffmpeg, pulls the transcript from captions (or Whisper API fallback), and hands the result to Claude so it can answer questions about what&#x27;s in the video.
argument-hint: &quot;&lt;video-url-or-path&gt; [question]&quot;
allowed-tools: Bash, Read, AskUserQuestion
homepage: https://github.com/bradautomates/claude-video
repository: https://github.com/bradautomates/claude-video
author: bradautomates
license: MIT
user-invocable: true
---

# /watch

You don&#x27;t have a video input; this skill gives you one. A Python script gets captions first, optionally downloads the video, extracts frames as JPEGs (scene-aware, or fast keyframes at `efficient` detail), gets a timestamped transcript (native captions first, then Whisper API as fallback), and prints frame paths. You then `Read` each frame path to see the images and combine them with the transcript to answer the user.

## Resolve `SKILL_DIR` (do this before any command)

Every `python3 ...` command below runs a bundled script under `SKILL_DIR/scripts/`. Set `SKILL_DIR` to the **absolute path of the directory containing THIS SKILL.md you just Read** — your harness told you that path in the Read result. The scripts are always a direct sibling of this file (`SKILL_DIR/scripts/watch.py`), in every install layout:

```
Read ~/.claude/plugins/cache/claude-video/watch/&lt;ver&gt;/skills/watch/SKILL.md → SKILL_DIR=…/skills/watch
Read ~/.codex/skills/watch/SKILL.md                                          → SKILL_DIR=~/.codex/skills/watch
Read ~/.agents/skills/watch/SKILL.md                                         → SKILL_DIR=~/.agents/skills/watch
```

Substitute that literal path for `${SKILL_DIR}` in every command. This works on every harness (Claude Code, Codex, Cursor, Gemini CLI, …) without relying on any harness-specific environment variable. Guard once at the start of a run:

```bash
SKILL_DIR=&quot;&lt;absolute path of the directory containing the SKILL.md you Read&gt;&quot;
if [ ! -f &quot;$SKILL_DIR/scripts/watch.py&quot; ]; then
  echo &quot;ERROR: scripts/watch.py not found under SKILL_DIR=$SKILL_DIR&quot; &gt;&amp;2
  echo &quot;Re-check the directory of the SKILL.md you Read and substitute it as SKILL_DIR.&quot; &gt;&amp;2
  exit 1
fi
```

## Step 0 — Setup preflight (runs every `/watch` invocation, silent on success)

**Python interpreter:** every `python3 ...` command in this skill is for macOS/Linux. On **Windows**, substitute `python` — the `python3` command on Windows is the Microsoft Store stub and will not run the script.

On the first `/watch` invocation in a session, use structured preflight so you can detect first-run setup:

```bash
python3 &quot;${SKILL_DIR}/scripts/setup.py&quot; --json
```

Branch on two fields:

- **`can_proceed: true` and `first_run: false`** → setup is already done (the user may have deliberately skipped a Whisper key — that&#x27;s allowed). Proceed to Step 1 without comment.
- **`first_run: true`** → genuine first-time setup. Do these in order:
  1. If `missing_binaries` is non-empty, run the installer first (it auto-installs on macOS / prints commands elsewhere — see below) and confirm the binaries land. **Do not skip this and jump to preferences.**
  2. Run the installer once more if needed so it scaffolds `~/.config/watch/.env` (it only writes the template when the file is absent, so let it create the file *before* you write any values into it).
  3. Encourage a Whisper API key and ask the watch-preference questions below, then write the selected values into `~/.config/watch/.env` and set `SETUP_COMPLETE=true`.
- **`can_proceed: false` and `first_run: false`** → setup was finished before but the environment regressed (e.g. `missing_binaries` after an OS change). Run the installer to remediate, then proceed. Don&#x27;t re-ask preferences.

A missing Whisper key is *encouraged to fix, not required*: on a genuine first run `status` will read `needs_key` even when binaries are present — that&#x27;s your cue to encourage a key, not a blocker.

On follow-up `/watch` calls in the same session, use the silent check:

```bash
python3 &quot;${SKILL_DIR}/scripts/setup.py&quot; --check
```

This is a &lt;100ms lookup. Exit 0 means /watch can run — this **includes a user who finished setup without a Whisper key** (keyless is allowed). On exit 0 the script emits **nothing** — proceed to Step 1 without comment. **Do NOT announce &quot;setup is complete&quot; to the user** — they don&#x27;t need a status message on every turn. The only acceptable user-visible output from Step 0 is when remediation is required.

On non-zero exit, follow the table:

| Exit | Meaning | Action |
|------|---------|--------|
| `2` | Missing binaries (`ffmpeg` / `ffprobe` / `yt-dlp`) | Run installer |
| `3` | Genuine first run with no Whisper API key | Run installer to scaffold `.env`, then encourage a key (the user may decline — proceed with `--no-whisper`) |
| `4` | Both missing | Run installer, then encourage a key |

Exit `3` only fires before the user has completed setup. Once `SETUP_COMPLETE=true` is written, a keyless install returns exit 0 and is never nagged again.

The installer is idempotent — safe to re-run:

```bash
python3 &quot;${SKILL_DIR}/scripts/setup.py&quot;
```

On macOS with Homebrew, it auto-installs `ffmpeg` and `yt-dlp`. On Linux/Windows, it prints the exact install commands for the user to run. It scaffolds `~/.config/watch/.env` with commented placeholders and default watch settings at `0600` perms.

**If an API key is still missing after install:** use `AskUserQuestion` to ask the user whether they have a Groq API key (preferred — cheaper, faster) or an OpenAI key. Then write it into `~/.config/watch/.env` — set the matching `GROQ_API_KEY=...` or `OPENAI_API_KEY=...` line. If they don&#x27;t want to set up Whisper, proceed with `--no-whisper` and tell them videos without native captions will come back frames-only.

**First-run watch preference:** after the installer has scaffolded `~/.config/watch/.env`, use `AskUserQuestion` to ask one question:

- Default detail (one dial). Present these as `AskUserQuestion` options in this exact order — lightest to heaviest — and keep `(recommended)` on `balanced` even though it is not first (do **not** reorder to put the recommended option first):
  - `transcript` — no frames at all, transcript only (skips video download when captions exist).
  - `efficient` — fast keyframe pass (cap 50).
  - `balanced` (recommended) — scene-aware frames (cap 100, default).
  - `token-burner` — scene-aware, uncapped (maximum fidelity; high token cost).

Write the answer directly into `~/.config/watch/.env` by setting the bare key on its own line — **no trailing inline comment** (a `# note` after the value can break parsing):

```bash
WATCH_DETAIL=balanced
```

Use the user&#x27;s selected value. If they skip the question, keep the recommended default. Once dependencies, the API-key choice, and this preference are handled, write or update `SETUP_COMPLETE=true` in the same file. Do not ask this preference question again when `SETUP_COMPLETE=true`.

**Structured mode (optional):** `python3 &quot;${SKILL_DIR}/scripts/setup.py&quot; --json` emits `{status, can_proceed, first_run, setup_complete, missing_binaries, whisper_backend, has_api_key, config_file, watch_detail, platform}` where `status` is one of `ready | needs_install | needs_key | needs_install_and_key`. `status` describes the *ideal* state (a key is encouraged, so a keyless first run reads `needs_key`); `can_proceed` is the operational gate (binaries present AND a key is set OR setup was already completed). Branch on `can_proceed`/`first_run` to decide whether to run; use `status` to decide what to encourage.

Within a single session, you can skip Step 0 on follow-up `/watch` calls — once `--check` returned 0, nothing about the environment changes between turns.

## When to use

- User pastes a video URL (YouTube, Vimeo, X, TikTok, Twitch clip, most yt-dlp-supported sites) and asks about it.
- User points at a local video file (`.mp4`, `.mov`, `.mkv`, `.webm`, etc.) and asks about it.
- User types `/watch &lt;url-or-path&gt; [question]`.

## Recommended limits

- **Best accuracy: videos under 10 minutes.** Frame coverage scales inversely with duration.
- **Universal rate cap: 2 fps.** The script never samples faster than 2 fps, even when a budget or `--fps` would imply more.
- **The frame ceiling is set by the detail mode** (`WATCH_DETAIL` in `~/.config/watch/.env`, or `--detail`), not a single global cap:
  - `transcript` → no frames
  - `efficient` → up to **50** (keyframes)
  - `balanced` (default) → up to **100** (scene-aware)
  - `token-burner` → **uncapped** (scene-aware; a soft warning prints past 250 frames)
  - `--max-frames N` overrides whichever cap the mode would otherwise use.
- **Full-video frame budget by duration.** Token cost grows with frame count, so the script targets a budget by duration. This budget sets the fps and the uniform-sampling fallback; scene-aware selection can fill up to the detail cap above, whichever is lower:
  - ≤30s → ~12-30 frames
  - 30s-1min → ~40 frames
  - 1-3min → ~60 frames
  - 3-10min → ~80 frames
  - \&gt;10min → up to the detail cap, sparsely spaced (warning printed)
- If the user hands you a long video, consider asking whether they want a specific section before burning tokens on a sparse scan.

## How to invoke

**Step 1 — parse the user input.** Separate the video source (URL or path) from any question the user asked. Example: `/watch https://youtu.be/abc what language is this in?` → source = `https://youtu.be/abc`, question = `what language is this in?`.

**Step 2 — run the watch script.** Pass the source verbatim. Do not shell-escape it yourself beyond normal quoting:

```bash
python3 &quot;${SKILL_DIR}/scripts/watch.py&quot; &quot;&lt;source&gt;&quot;
```

Optional flags:
- `--detail transcript|efficient|balanced|token-burner` — fidelity/speed dial. `transcript` = no frames (transcript only, skips video download when captions exist); `efficient` = fast keyframes (cap 50); `balanced` = scene-aware frames (cap 100); `token-burner` = scene-aware, uncapped.
- `--start T` / `--end T` — focus on a section. Accepts `SS`, `MM:SS`, or `HH:MM:SS`. When either is set, fps auto-scales denser (see &quot;Focusing on a section&quot; below).
- `--timestamps T1,T2,…` — grab a frame at each of these absolute timestamps (`SS`, `MM:SS`, or `HH:MM:SS`). Use this after reading the transcript to capture deictic moments the presenter flags (&quot;look here&quot;, &quot;as you can see&quot;, &quot;notice this&quot;) that visual selection alone may miss. See &quot;Transcript-cue frames&quot; below.
- `--max-frames N` — override the preset cap for tighter token budget (e.g. `--max-frames 40`)
- `--resolution W` — change frame width in px (default 512; bump to 1024 only if the user needs to read on-screen text)
- `--fps F` — override auto-fps (clamped to 2 fps max)
- `--out-dir DIR` — keep working files somewhere specific (default: an auto-generated tmp dir)
- `--whisper groq|openai` — force a specific Whisper backend (default: prefer Groq if both keys exist)
- `--no-whisper` — disable the Whisper fallback entirely (frames-only if no captions)
- `--no-dedup` — keep near-duplicate frames. By default a frame-delta pass drops frames that are visually near-identical to the previous kept one (held slides, static screen recordings, paused video) so the frame budget goes to distinct content; the report&#x27;s **Frames** line notes how many were dropped. Pass this only if the user needs every sampled frame (e.g. judging subtle frame-to-frame motion).

### Focusing on a section (higher frame rate)

When the user asks about a specific moment — &quot;what happens at the 2 minute mark?&quot;, &quot;zoom into 0:45 to 1:00&quot;, &quot;the first 10 seconds&quot; — pass `--start` and/or `--end`. The script switches to focused-mode budgets, which are denser than full-video budgets (still capped at 2 fps, and still bounded by the detail-mode cap — the counts below assume the default `balanced` cap of 100; `efficient` tops out at 50):

- ≤5s → 2 fps (up to 10 frames)
- 5-15s → 2 fps (up to 30 frames)
- 15-30s → ~2 fps (up to 60 frames)
- 30-60s → ~1.3 fps (up to 80 frames)
- 60-180s → ~0.6 fps (100 frames, capped)

Focused mode is the right call for:
- Any moment/range the user names explicitly (&quot;around 2:30&quot;, &quot;the intro&quot;, &quot;the last 30 seconds&quot;).
- Any video longer than ~10 minutes where the user&#x27;s question is about a specific part — running focused on the relevant section is far more useful than a sparse scan of the whole thing.
- Re-runs after a full scan didn&#x27;t have enough detail in some region.

Transcript is auto-filtered to the same range. Frame timestamps are absolute (real video timeline, not offset-from-start).

Examples:
```bash
# Last 10 seconds of a 1 minute video
python3 &quot;${SKILL_DIR}/scripts/watch.py&quot; video.mp4 --start 50 --end 60

# Zoom into 2:15 → 2:45 at 2 fps (60 frames)
python3 &quot;${SKILL_DIR}/scripts/watch.py&quot; &quot;$URL&quot; --start 2:15 --end 2:45 --fps 2

# From 1h12m to the end of the video
python3 &quot;${SKILL_DIR}/scripts/watch.py&quot; &quot;$URL&quot; --start 1:12:00
```

**Step 3 — Read every frame path the script lists.** The Read tool renders JPEGs directly as images for you. Read all frames in a single message (parallel tool calls) so you see them together. The frames are in chronological order with a `t=MM:SS` timestamp so you can align them to the transcript.

**Step 4 — answer the user.** You now have two streams of evidence:
- **Frames** — what&#x27;s on screen at each timestamp
- **Transcript** — what&#x27;s said at each timestamp. The report&#x27;s header shows the source (`captions` = yt-dlp pulled native subs; `whisper (groq)` or `whisper (openai)` = transcribed by API).

If the user asked a specific question, answer it directly citing timestamps. If they didn&#x27;t ask anything, summarize what happens in the video — structure, key moments, notable visuals, spoken content.

This holds for `transcript` detail too: even with no frames, produce a **summary** like the other modes — do not paste the full transcript into chat. Synthesize structure, key moments, and spoken content with timestamps; quote only the lines that matter. Offer the raw transcript only if the user explicitly asks for it.

**Step 5 — clean up.** The script prints a working directory at the end. If the user isn&#x27;t going to ask follow-ups about this video, delete it with `rm -rf &lt;dir&gt;`. If they might, leave it in place.

## Detail and frames

Default behavior comes from `~/.config/watch/.env`:

- `WATCH_DETAIL=transcript|efficient|balanced|token-burner` (default: `balanced`)

At `transcript` detail, captions are enough to return a report without downloading video. If captions are missing, the script downloads audio only and tries Whisper. If no transcript can be produced, it reports the limitation clearly; re-run with `--detail balanced` for frames.

At `efficient` detail, the script downloads the video and extracts **keyframes only** (`ffmpeg -skip_frame nokey`) — a near-instant pass that lands frames on scene cuts. If a clip has fewer than 4 keyframes it falls back to uniform sampling.

At `balanced` / `token-burner` detail, the script extracts **scene-aware** frames: ffmpeg scene-change selection first, falling back to uniform sampling only when the video is effectively static. `balanced` caps at 100 frames; `token-burner` is uncapped. Frame report lines include both timestamp and selection reason. Extracted images are clamped to a maximum 1998px height for Claude Read compatibility.

## Transcript-cue frames

Visual frame selection (scene/keyframe) can miss the moments a presenter explicitly flags — &quot;look here&quot;, &quot;as you can see&quot;, &quot;notice this&quot;, &quot;watch what happens&quot; — because pointing at a slide is often a *low* visual change. `--timestamps` lets you force a frame at those exact moments. **You** decide which moments matter, by reading the transcript:

1. Run once at `--detail transcript` (or any detail) to get the timestamped transcript.
2. Scan it for deictic cues — phrases where the speaker directs attention to something on screen. This is a judgment call (ignore rhetorical &quot;look, the point is…&quot;); that&#x27;s why it&#x27;s done by you, not a regex.
3. Re-run with `--timestamps 4:32,7:10,9:55` (absolute source times). For a URL, point the second run at the **downloaded local file** in the work dir so it doesn&#x27;t re-download.

Behavior:
- **Additive by default.** Cue frames (`reason=transcript-cue`) are merged into whatever `--detail` already selected, in chronological order.
- **Pinned and counted first.** Cue frames are reserved against the frame cap before the detail engine runs, so they&#x27;re never evicted by even-sampling.
- **Honors focus mode.** With `--start/--end`, any cue timestamp outside the window is dropped (reported in the summary). Coordinates are always absolute source time.
- **Cue-only frames.** `--detail transcript --timestamps …` skips scene/keyframe sampling and returns *only* the cue frames (it will download the video to do so, since frames need pixels).

## Transcription

The script gets a timestamped transcript in one of two ways:

1. **Native captions (free, preferred).** yt-dlp pulls manual or auto-generated subtitles from the source platform if available.
2. **Whisper API fallback.** If no captions came back (or the source is a local file), the script extracts audio (`ffmpeg -vn -ac 1 -ar 16000 -b:a 64k`, ~0.5 MB/min) and uploads it to whichever Whisper API has a key configured:
   - **Groq** — `whisper-large-v3`. Preferred default: cheaper, faster. Get a key at console.groq.com/keys.
   - **OpenAI** — `whisper-1`. Fallback. Get a key at platform.openai.com/api-keys.

Both keys live in `~/.config/watch/.env`. The script prefers Groq when both are set; override with `--whisper openai` to force OpenAI. Use `--no-whisper` to skip the fallback entirely.

## Failure modes and handling

- **Setup preflight failed** → run `python3 &quot;${SKILL_DIR}/scripts/setup.py&quot;` (auto-installs ffmpeg/yt-dlp via brew on macOS, scaffolds the `.env`). For API key, ask the user via `AskUserQuestion` and write it to `~/.config/watch/.env`.
- **No transcript available** → captions missing AND (no Whisper key OR Whisper API failed). Script prints a hint pointing to setup. Proceed frames-only and tell the user.
- **Long video warning printed** → acknowledge it in your answer. Offer to re-run focused on a specific section via `--start`/`--end` rather than a sparse full-video scan.
- **Download fails** → yt-dlp&#x27;s error goes to stderr. If it&#x27;s a login-required or region-locked video, tell the user plainly; do not keep retrying.
- **Whisper request fails** → the error is printed to stderr (likely: invalid key or rate limit). Audio over the API&#x27;s 25 MB upload cap is split into chunks and transcribed automatically, so length alone won&#x27;t fail it; if some chunks fail the transcript is partial and the dropped chunks are noted on stderr. The report will say &quot;none available&quot; only if every chunk fails. You can retry with `--whisper openai` if Groq failed (or vice versa).

## Token efficiency

This skill burns tokens primarily on frames. Order of magnitude:
- 80 frames at 512px wide is roughly 50-80k image tokens depending on aspect ratio.
- The transcript is cheap (a few thousand tokens at most for a 10-minute video).
- Bumping `--resolution` to 1024 roughly quadruples the image tokens per frame. Only do it when necessary.

If you already watched a video this session and the user asks a follow-up, do **not** re-run the script — you already have the frames and transcript in context. Just answer from what you have.

## Security &amp; Permissions

**What this skill does:**
- Runs `yt-dlp` locally to download the video and pull native captions when the source supports them (public data; the request goes directly to whatever host the URL points at)
- Runs `ffmpeg` / `ffprobe` locally to extract frames as JPEGs and, when Whisper is needed, a mono 16 kHz audio clip
- Sends the extracted audio clip to Groq&#x27;s Whisper API (`api.groq.com/openai/v1/audio/transcriptions`) when `GROQ_API_KEY` is set (preferred — cheaper, faster)
- Sends the extracted audio clip to OpenAI&#x27;s audio transcription API (`api.openai.com/v1/audio/transcriptions`) when `OPENAI_API_KEY` is set and Groq is not, or when `--whisper openai` is forced
- Writes the downloaded video, frames, audio, and an intermediate transcript to a working directory under the system temp dir (or `--out-dir` if specified) so Claude can `Read` them
- Reads / creates `~/.config/watch/.env` (mode `0600`) to store the Whisper API key(s) and a `SETUP_COMPLETE` marker. As a fallback, also reads `.env` in the current working directory

**What this skill does NOT do:**
- Does not upload the video itself to any API — only the extracted audio goes out, and only when native captions are missing AND Whisper is not disabled with `--no-whisper`
- Does not access any platform account (no login, no session cookies, no posting) — yt-dlp only ever requests public data
- Does not share API keys between providers (Groq key only goes to `api.groq.com`, OpenAI key only goes to `api.openai.com`)
- Does not log, cache, or write API keys to stdout, stderr, or output files
- Does not persist anything outside the working directory and `~/.config/watch/.env` — clean up the working directory when you&#x27;re done (Step 5)

**Bundled scripts:** `scripts/watch.py` (entry point), `scripts/download.py` (yt-dlp wrapper), `scripts/frames.py` (ffmpeg frame extraction), `scripts/transcribe.py` (caption selection + Whisper orchestration), `scripts/whisper.py` (Groq / OpenAI clients), `scripts/setup.py` (preflight + installer)

Review scripts before first use to verify behavior.

  </file>
</slice>
